Finding Aid for the Allan Katz Scripts PASC.0058
UCLA Library Special Collections
Allan Katz scripts
1982-1986
UCLA Library Special Collections
Katz, Allan
PASC.0058
5.0 Linear Feet (12 boxes)
Allan Katz was a television writer and producer. The collection consists of scripts related to Katz's career including Adam's House, Charlie & Company, and Sam.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9919729593606533
Biography
There is limited biographical information about Allan Katz. Television writer and producer Allan Katz' credits include Rowan and Martin's Laugh-In, M*A*S*H, Charlie & Comany, and Adam's House among others.
Scope and Content
The collection consists of scripts related to the career of television writer and producer, Allan Katz. The bulk of the scripts represent the television series Charlie & Company and includes drafts and revisions for each episode. Additionally there are scripts for Adam's House and pilot scripts for The Goodbye Girl and Sam.
Organization and Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically by production title.
Television producers and directors -- Archives.; Katz, Allan -- Archives
- ADAMS HOUSE: HOUSE IS NOT A HOME (A), 3/26/1982 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  General note
  Revised final draft.
  Writers: Katz, Allan
- ADAMS HOUSE: HOUSE IS NOT A HOME (A), 3/15/1982 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  Third revised draft.
- ADAMS HOUSE: HOUSE IS NOT A HOME (A), 3/24/1982 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  Final draft.
- CHARLIE & COMPANY (PILOT), 3/28/1985 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  Second draft. Three copies, two with annotations.
- CHARLIE & COMPANY (PILOT), 4/3/1985 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  Final draft. Revisions included.
- CHARLIE & COMPANY (PILOT), 4/4/1985 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  Revised second draft.
- CHARLIE & COMPANY BEAUS AND ARROWS (Box 6, Folder 4)
  Revisions only.
- CHARLIE & COMPANY BEAUS AND ARROWS, 11/11/1985 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  Writers: Kagan, Michael; Katz, Allan (story)
- CHARLIE & COMPANY BEAUS AND ARROWS, 11/6/1985 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  First draft. Includes revised first draft.
- CHARLIE & COMPANY BEAUS AND ARROWS, 10/15/1985 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  Preliminary draft. With revised preliminary draft.
  Writers: Kagan, Michael
- CHARLIE & COMPANY BUDDY, CAN YOU SPARE MY DIME, 8/15/1985 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  Revised first draft. Three copies, one with production schedule, cast list and teaser.
  Writers: Gilbert, Gary
- CHARLIE & COMPANY BUDDY, CAN YOU SPARE MY DIME, 7/16/1985 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  Preliminary draft.
- CHARLIE & COMPANY BUDDY, CAN YOU SPARE MY DIME, 7/30/1985 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  First draft.
- CHARLIE & COMPANY BUDDY, CAN YOU SPARE MY DIME, 7/30/1985 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  Revised preliminary draft. Two copies, one with cast list, set list and teaser.
- CHARLIE & COMPANY BUDDY, CAN YOU SPARE MY DIME?, 8/19/1985 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Final draft. Two copies, one with annotations.
- CHARLIE & COMPANY BUDDY, CAN YOU SPARE MY DIME?, 8/15/1985 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Revised first draft. Two copies, includes second Rev.draft revisions.
- CHARLIE & COMPANY BUDDY, CAN YOU SPARE MY DIME?, 8/14/1985 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  First draft. Two copies, one with annotations.
- CHARLIE & COMPANY DON'T TAKE MY SON, PLEASE (Box 8, Folder 5)
- CHARLIE & COMPANY DON'T TAKE MY SON, PLEASE, 12/26/1985 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  Writers: Richmond, Bill
- CHARLIE & COMPANY DON'T TAKE MY SON, PLEASE, 1/2/1986 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- CHARLIE & COMPANY DON'T TAKE MY SON, PLEASE, 1/6/1986 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- CHARLIE & COMPANY EASY FOR YOU TO SAY, 8/7/1985 (Box 11, Folder 2)
- CHARLIE & COMPANY EASY FOR YOU TO SAY, 8/7/1985 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  Revised first draft. Three copies with annotations.
- CHARLIE & COMPANY EASY FOR YOU TO SAY, 8/12/1985 (Box 11, Folder 4)
- CHARLIE & COMPANY EASY FOR YOU TO SAY (Box 11, Folder 5)
- CHARLIE & COMPANY EASY FOR YOU TO SAY, 7/8/1985 (Box 11, Folder 1)
- CHARLIE & COMPANY FOR THE LOVE OF LAUREN (Box 5, Folder 9)
  Teasers and revisions
- CHARLIE & COMPANY FOR THE LOVE OF LAUREN, 10/24/1985 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  Revised preliminary draft. Includes second revised preliminary draft.
- CHARLIE & COMPANY FOR THE LOVE OF LAUREN, 10/29/1985 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  First draft. Revised first draft and second revised first draft.
- CHARLIE & COMPANY FOR THE LOVE OF LAUREN, 11/4/1985 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- CHARLIE & COMPANY FOR THE LOVE OF LAUREN, 10/21/1985 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- CHARLIE & COMPANY HAPPY ANNIVERSARY... SORT OF (Box 4, Folder 10)
- CHARLIE & COMPANY HAPPY ANNIVERSARY... SORT OF, 10/11/1985 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  Rough draft.
- CHARLIE & COMPANY HAPPY ANNIVERSARY... SORT OF, 10/16/1985 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- CHARLIE & COMPANY HAPPY ANNIVERSARY... SORT OF, 10/21/1985 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- CHARLIE & COMPANY HAPPY ANNIVERSARY... SORT OF (Box 5, Folder 4)
  Teasers and revisions.
- CHARLIE & COMPANY HAPPY ANNIVERSARY... SORT OF, 10/17/1985 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  Revised first draft. With second revised first draft.
- CHARLIE & COMPANY HERE'S RACHEL (Box 7, Folder 6)
- CHARLIE & COMPANY HERE'S RACHEL, 12/11/1985 (Box 7, Folder 7)
- CHARLIE & COMPANY HERE'S RACHEL, 12/12/1985 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  Revised first draft. Two copies, one with annotations.
- CHARLIE & COMPANY HERE'S RACHEL, 12/16/1985 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  Final draft with revisions and teasers.
  Writers: Katz, Allen
- CHARLIE & COMPANY LIKE FATHER, LIKE SON (Box 2, Folder 8)
  Story outline and revisions.
  Writers: Aidem, Monty; Murphy, Gary
- CHARLIE & COMPANY LIKE FATHER, LIKE SON, 9/23/1985 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- CHARLIE & COMPANY LIKE FATHER, LIKE SON, 9/9/1985 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- CHARLIE & COMPANY LIKE FATHER, LIKE SON, 9/18/1985 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- CHARLIE & COMPANY LIKE FATHER, LIKE SON, 9/19/1985 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- CHARLIE & COMPANY MUGGERS OR US, 7/8/1985 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- CHARLIE & COMPANY MUGGERS OR US (Box 12, Folder 6)
  Teaser and revisions only.
- CHARLIE & COMPANY MUGGERS OR US, 8/26/1985 (Box 12, Folder 5)
- CHARLIE & COMPANY MUGGERS OR US, 7/26/1985 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  Second draft. Two copies, one with annotations.
- CHARLIE & COMPANY MUGGERS OR US, 8/22/1985 (Box 12, Folder 3)
- CHARLIE & COMPANY MUGGERS OR US, 8/21/1985 (Box 12, Folder 2)
- CHARLIE & COMPANY MUGGERS OR US, 7/19/1985 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  Preliminary draft. Two copies, one with annotations.
- CHARLIE & COMPANY MUGGERS OR US, 8/8/1985 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Revised preliminary draft.
- CHARLIE & COMPANY MUGGERS OR US, 8/12/1985 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- CHARLIE & COMPANY OPERATION RICHMOND, 9/18/1985 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  Rough draft. Includes synopsis; formerly titled "It Only Hurts When I'm Awake"
  Writers: Ferrier, Gary; Tadman, Aubrey
- CHARLIE & COMPANY OPERATION RICHMOND (Box 4, Folder 9)
  Revisions, teasers and tentative rehearsal and taping schedule.
- CHARLIE & COMPANY OPERATION RICHMOND, 10/10/1985 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- CHARLIE & COMPANY OPERATION RICHMOND, 10/1/1985 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- CHARLIE & COMPANY OPERATION RICHMOND, 10/14/1985 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- CHARLIE & COMPANY OPERATION RICHMOND, 10/9/1985 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- CHARLIE & COMPANY RACHEL AND THE STRANGER, 2/3/1986 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  Writers: Sage, Liz
- CHARLIE & COMPANY RACHEL AND THE STRANGER, 1/30/1986 (Box 9, Folder 4)
- CHARLIE & COMPANY RACHEL AND THE STRANGER, 1/22/1986 (Box 9, Folder 2)
- CHARLIE & COMPANY RACHEL AND THE STRANGER, 1/29/1986 (Box 9, Folder 3)
- CHARLIE & COMPANY RENT AND RAVE, 11/12/1985 (Box 6, Folder 10)
- CHARLIE & COMPANY RENT AND RAVE, 11/14/1985 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- CHARLIE & COMPANY RENT AND RAVE, 11/27/1985 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  Second revised preliminary draft. Includes third revised preliminary draft.
- CHARLIE & COMPANY RENT AND RAVE, 12/4/1985 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  First draft. Includes two copies of revised first draft, one with annotations.
- CHARLIE & COMPANY RENT AND RAVE, 12/9/1985 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- CHARLIE & COMPANY RENT AND RAVE (Box 7, Folder 5)
- CHARLIE & COMPANY SILENT KNIGHT, 11/18/1985 (Box 6, Folder 8)
- CHARLIE & COMPANY SILENT KNIGHT, 11/14/1985 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- CHARLIE & COMPANY SILENT KNIGHT (Box 6, Folder 9)
- CHARLIE & COMPANY SILENT KNIGHT, 11/13/1985 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- CHARLIE & COMPANY SILENT KNIGHT, 11/8/1985 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- CHARLIE & COMPANY WHEN YOU LEAST EXPECT IT, 1/8/1986 (Box 8, Folder 7)
- CHARLIE & COMPANY WHEN YOU LEAST EXPECT IT, 1/13/1986 (Box 9, Folder 1)
- CHARLIE & COMPANY WHEN YOU LEAST EXPECT IT, 1/9/1986 (Box 8, Folder 8)
- CHARLIE & COMPANY WHEN YOU LEAST EXPECT IT (Box 8, Folder 9)
  Rough draft, preliminary draft
- CHARLIE & COMPANY WHEN YOU LEAST EXPECT IT, 1/6/1986 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  Second revised preliminary draft.
- CHARLIE & COMPANY WHO'S WATCHING THE ROAD?, 8/29/1985 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- CHARLIE & COMPANY WHO'S WATCHING THE ROAD?, 9/1/1985 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- CHARLIE & COMPANY WHO'S WATCHING THE ROAD?, 9/4/1985 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- CHARLIE & COMPANY WHO'S WATCHING THE ROAD?, 9/9/1985 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  Revised first draft. Three copies, one with annotations.
- CHARLIE & COMPANY WHO'S WATCHING THE ROAD? (Box 2, Folder 2)
  Revisions and teasers.
- CHARLIE & COMPANY WHO'S WATCHING THE ROAD?, 9/9/1985 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- CHARLIE & COMPANY WILL BE AROUND, 10/2/1985 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- CHARLIE & COMPANY WILL BE AROUND, 9/24/1985 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- CHARLIE & COMPANY WILL BE AROUND, 9/6/1985 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- CHARLIE & COMPANY WILL BE AROUND, 10/7/1985 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- CHARLIE & COMPANY WILL BE AROUND (Box 4, Folder 4)
- CHARLIE & COMPANY WILL BE AROUND, 10/3/1985 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- CHARLIE & COMPANY WON'T YOU COME BACK, AUNT RACHEL, 1/3/1986 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  Preliminary draft. Teaser included.
- CHARLIE & COMPANY WON'T YOU COME BACK, AUNT RACHEL, 1/29/1986 (Box 9, Folder 7)
- CHARLIE & COMPANY WORLD ACCORDING TO JIM (The), 9/5/1985 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- CHARLIE & COMPANY WORLD ACCORDING TO JIM (The), 9/9/1985 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  Revised preliminary draft. Two copies, one with annotations.
- CHARLIE & COMPANY WORLD ACCORDING TO JIM (The), 9/12/1985 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- CHARLIE & COMPANY WORLD ACCORDING TO JIM (The), 9/16/1985 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- CHARLIE & COMPANY WORLD ACCORDING TO JIM, THE, 9/11/1985 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  First draft. Two copies, one with annotations
- CHARLIE & COMPANY WORLD ACCORDING TO JIM, THE (Box 3, Folder 6)
- GOODBYE GIRL, THE: PILOT, 4/10/1980 (Box 10, Folder 6)
- SAM: (PILOT), 3/4/1985 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  Second draft. Four copies, three with annotations.
- SAM: (PILOT), 3/21/1985 (Box 10, Folder 3)
- SAM: (PILOT) (Box 10, Folder 4)
- SAM: (PILOT) (Box 10, Folder 5)
  Cast and staff lists; distribution list; memos; production schedule.